(speaking Spanish)
He's not gonna stop until
he knows who did this.
You fuck this up. and
I'm gonna kill you.
ALEJANDRO: There are soldiers
in the jungle. waiting for me
to deliver supplies and weapons.
- Give this to Alejandro.
Not flying into
Hawthorne anymore.
Where the hell are we
going to land. then?
FRANKLIN: Saw Pops last night.
- You all right?
- Tough to say.
You poach customers. you
gonna get blowback.
(grunts)
Where's my money?
Aah!
(gunshot) This is fucked.
I'm out.
You lasted longer than I
thought you would. kid.
(tape ripping)
(plane creaks)
(clank)
(inhales slowly)
(plastic crinkles)
(exhales slowly)
♪♪
(exhales)
(hollow thump)
(rattling)
(exhaling deeply)
I know.
Landing gear was my idea.
I know... that.
But...
You know what?
The operative word there...
is "land." buddy.
You... you've done nothing
but blow smoke up my ass
since we started this
thing. and you know it.
So... so. then you
give me one reason.
just one reason. why I
was supposed to believe
there wasn't gonna be
yet another shitshow waiting
for us at Hawthorne.
I didn't think so.
I'm sorry.
But. you know. you gave me
no choice in the matter.
(sighs) You gave me
no choice at all.
♪♪
(speaking Spanish)
(women speaking
indistinctly in Spanish)
(door opens. closes)
Surprised that your sorority
sisters can't sell more cocaine.
I'm sorry.
Is that sarcasm?
(doors creak)
(zipper whirs)
We're banging our heads
against the wall
that Ramiro placed between
us and the entire Eastside.
We're not gonna be able to buy
the next shipment on time.
(scoffs) Well. tomorrow's
a big opportunity.
(beads rattle) Lots of people looking
to celebrate this great nation
by getting fucking wasted.
Hopefully. we'll be able
to make up some ground.
Do you have somewhere
to go tomorrow?
(speaking Spanish)
Uh...
Okay. Good.
Happy 4th. Oso.
(door opens. closes)
(brakes squeal.
engine turns off)
(door creaks open)
CISSY: Hey.
(photo crinkles. door closes)
'Sup?
I pulled them lawn chairs
to take over to Jerome's
like you asked.
I asked you that yesterday.
Remember the 4th parties
we used to have
here at the house? (chuckles)
I remember them being
a lot of work.
Dad didn't think so.
You know. for somebody who has
zero love for this country.
the man had no shame using it
as an excuse to throw down.
That year all his friends
from Oakland stopped by?
Shit was live.
(package rustles)
When I was in the
garage. I found this.
How is it the first
time I'm seeing these?
Ain't no big conspiracy.
Just forgot they were there.
(beads rattling) Almost
didn't recognize the man.
Shit being out of
focus didn't help.
Can't say it was my best.
You took this? Mm-hmm.
Mama got talent. (Chuckles)
You ever think about
picking it back up?
Takin' pictures
doesn't pay bills.
Neither does that
"sick" bullshit
you been disrespecting
us both with.
I quit Cho's.
Didn't want you stressin'
about the money.
so I kept it quiet.
You right about the money.
And it gon' hurt.
But not for long. 'cause
you're going back.
Not to no liquor store
if you don't want.
But I can't abide you
being idle. either.
Know all too well
where that leads.
(rustling)
(refrigerator door closes)
No. we gonna be all right.
I'm-a see to it.
I promise.
Yeah. okay.
I need to get on these ribs.
You want me to make you
something while I'm up?
Already ate.
♪♪
(The Universals' New
Generation playing)
♪ Everybody now is
doing their thing ♪
♪ Everything now is...
(indistinct conversation)
♪ If you wanna have
a groovy time ♪
♪ Just grab your...
I done told them folks.
I'm the one started it.
This ain't his fault!
I mean. I don't know why y'all are
in my personal business anyway.
Here. take what I got.
(coins clattering)
You want it all? Here.
Just take it all.
'cause I ain't got
damn no time for this.
Don't make no sense. You
know that's some bullshit.
I've been sitting here all day.
All day!
I gotta go to work.
He gotta go to work.
MAN: Just shut up!
Yeah. desk sergeant...
No. you shut up! Shut
your damn mouth!
WOMAN: Nobody talkin' to you anyway!
Damn!
Everybody in here got
something to do.
Not like we ain't got no lives.
He a good man. Y'all don't know him
like I know him. (Telephone ringing)
He wouldn't do
something like this.
Make no sense. ♪ New generation
I'm ready to go. This is
just too much for one day.
Too doggone much. ♪
Talkin' 'bout love
Y'all don't know him the way I know him.
♪ Talkin' 'bout love
I love him and he loves me.
Oh. no. (Door opens)
(door slams closed)
(exhales deeply. inhales deeply)
(people speaking
in Spanish on TV)
(sighs deeply) (siren
wailing in distance)
MAN: It tastes like cardboard.
(laughter)
WOMAN: Excuse me? You picked
that at the store. young man.
(door creaks open)
(inhales sharply)
(chuckles. speaking Spanish)
Well. come on. We're
already late.
(sighs) Late for what?
My family's party?
Oh.
(exhales) Maybe it's
not a good idea.
Why not? My father and uncle
know you do collections for me.
It'd be more strange
if you didn't.
You have a clean shirt? A tie?
No?
You need to borrow one?
(urinating)
Oh. I'm gonna make
this one an easy one.
Oh...
Uh. 'cause... which
side lost more men?
Uh. Lexington and Concord.
(imitates buzzer)
(zips pants) Wrong.
Because the red coats
got the worst of it
with. uh. 273 confirmed
killed. missing. or wounded
to our 95. which.
uh. makes you...
0 for...
13.
Jesus. Al.
Hey. you gotta get
your shit together.
(creaking)
You're like a goddamn
soup sandwich.
Fucking soup sandwich.
My old man used that
nugget like he...
fucking invented
a soup sandwich.
(creaking. wind blowing)
Come on.
Quit whining.
You know. as if I'd
have missed even one.
I'd have got...
Not like it mattered.
because not even
his monumental
prickdom or whatever
could stop me from
loving the 4th of July.
Tetherball. Bottle rockets.
You know. not to take
anything away from...
how I'm currently
spending the holiday.
Stranded in a Mexican desert
with a Nicaraguan invalid
and 75 kilos of
Peruvian cocaine.
(bird calling)
God bless America.
(wind gusting)
No!
Shit!
Shit.
(panting) Oh.
(wind gusting)
Goddamn it!
(exhales sharply)
Oh. God.
(grunts)
Shit.
Come on.
We just lost a half a
day's worth of water.
We only had a day's worth left!
Did you hear me? Want me
to do the math for you?
(creaking. wind
gusting) You think so?
So here's the deal. You're
gonna get off your ass.
you're gonna get
in that cockpit.
and you're gonna fly us
the fuck outta here!
You hear me?!
(slaps)
Look alive. fucker!
(gasping)
You need some help. Jerome?
Yeah. get that door for me.
All right.
TEDDY PENDERGRASS:
♪ I'm losin' again
(mouth full) Hey. who put the bot...
Get them bottles off my damn...
goddamn on my speakers.
WOMAN: Hi. girl! What's up?!
♪ Think I'd better let it go
Touching my goddamn speakers.
(turns up volume) CHILD: No. over here!
Hurry up!
♪ This is like
another love TKO ♪
Hey. baby. How you doin'?
♪ Oh. oh. oh What up. Mike?
Yeah! ♪ Think I'd
better let it go
♪ What you think about it. girl?
♪ Unh! Oh. all right.
Y'all. ♪ Oh. yeah
♪ TKO
♪ Mm-hmm
♪ Tried to take
control of the love ♪
♪ Love took control of me
♪ 'Cause you lose all
thoughts. sense of time ♪
♪ And have a change of mind
♪ Takin' the bumps
and the bruises ♪
♪ Of all the things
of a two-time loser ♪
There's my man!
♪ Tryin' to hold on.
faith is gone ♪
♪ It's just another sad
song What's up. girl?
Damn! What you got here?
My daddy call it bread pudding.
More like brick puddin'.
Andre here?
Please. He working late
all weekend anyway.
Hmm. All weekend. huh?
Good to see you ain't
been arrested yet.
What you talkin' about?
Like you don't know.
Mm-hmm. Cheers.
Mm-hmm. cheers.
Ol' boy still checkin' me out?
Yeah. girl. he still on you.
(laughs)
Mm-hmm.
Now bend over. girl. Bend over.
Yeah! (Laughs)
(laughs) You need to stop.
Rocking it there. (laughs)
You know that's how he like it.
Rock it. baby. Rock it.
Ooh! (Laughs)
Hell. naw. (speaks
indistinctly) Cissy.
Wait. wait. wait. wait. wait.
Cissy. Unh-unh.
♪ Tried to take
control of love ♪
Explain yourself. All
right. Mom. hold up.
Whatever it is. this ain't
the day or the time.
You need to bounce now.
Get your ass on up out of here.
Why you in my face?
Drunk. high. sober. I
don't give a damn.
Nobody wants you here.
Unh-unh. You don't need
to say shit to him.
Need a moment with Franklin.
He don't need nothing from you.
A half-moment then. damn!
Just let me thank him.
Woke up in the clink
this morning.
I'd still be there if he
hadn't bailed me out.
♪♪
Went and found him
before he got up.
♪ Think I'd better let it go
I. uh...
♪ Looks like another love TKO
If you gonna be here.
you're gonna clean up.
You know where the bathroom is.
♪ Whoa. yes
♪ Mmm. mmm. mmm
♪ Oh. sometimes. sometimes I
just feel like I wanna say ♪
♪ Mmm. mmm
♪ Looks like another love TKO
♪ Tired of gettin' beat
up by love ♪ (door opens)
♪ Think I'd better let it go
(door closes)
♪♪
♪ Another love TKO ♪ Yeah. yeah
(Directory's Feel It
in Your Bones playing)
(shower running)
(beads rattling)
The pictures wasn't good enough?
You had to drag his
stank ass here?
It ain't like that. Mom.
He came on his own.
Nigga bail himself out
the goddamn pokey?
Where you get that money from?
Had some saved.
How much? Couple hundred.
Day after you tell me
you quit your damn job.
(indistinct conversations)
I can't do this. Franklin.
Not again.
You know how it starts.
Ma. you the one
who let him stay.
Don't get the shit twisted.
This here is a single
act of kindness.
That no-good ass nigga ain't
nothing but a hobo to me.
One hour tops. and you
showing him the door.
♪♪
♪ Gonna find ya
♪ I'm gonna find ya
♪♪
(children shouting playfully)
♪ I'm gonna find ya
Franklin!
What's up with your Pops?
(laughs)
You didn't want a damn thing
to do with him the other day.
Now he up in there
using our soap?
(mouth full) Ask the
boy a real question.
like when he gonna
return my pistol.
Look here. we gonna have to
have a real conversation
about why you had
to lose that piece?
Not as far as I'm concerned.
(indistinct conversations)
♪♪
Lucia's place. huh?
Mauricio's. yeah.
So she grew up here. huh?
Psh.
You ask too many questions.
Vamos.
♪♪
(indistinct conversations
in Spanish)
I need one second. okay? Yeah.
Oso! (Chuckles)
Hello!
Thought you had
other plans today?
That what he told you?
(Lucia chuckles)
Hey. it's a good thing you're here.
It'll be fun.
(laughs)
Hey. Tío!
(speaking Spanish)
Who's this? My man Gustavo.
Gustavo. mi papá. Ramiro.
Mucho gusto. señor.
He's the guy I was
talking to you about.
You should speak with him.
Let him tell you himself
how he can help us.
Right. Oso?
Huh?
(speaks Spanish)
Come on.
Where you going? Wanna talk to you.
Come here.
Yeah. you enjoying that drink?
Yep. Good. I'm glad.
You fucking crazy?
You want him sitting
with your father?
You trying to put a noose
around all our fucking necks?
Not all of ours.
My dad finds out. you think I'm
the one catching a bullet?
I'm his only son.
Chin up. cousin.
Nobody knows anything yet.
So here's what
you're gonna do...
Keep your head up.
smile that big fucking
smile of yours.
and be calm.
That's it.
Say it.
♪♪
(shovel scrapes)
(wind blowing)
(panting)
(grunts)
(bird calling)
(bag thuds)
(door creaking)
(breathing deeply)
(engine starts)
I need... help.
(engine chugging loudly)
What the fuck? Come on. Um...
(exhales sharply)
(sighs deeply)
(turns off engine)
Fuck!
Jerome. get your crazy ass down.
Now. Cissy. look. I'm just
getting started up here.
(chuckles)
LEON: Just hear the man out. I
don't need to hear a damn thing.
I'm trying to keep
this shit low-key.
Look. all I'm saying is
strength in numbers.
You ask me. we already
one nigga over capacity.
(scoffs) All I need
is another big mouth
puttin' my business
out on the street.
If you haven't
noticed. Franklin.
your business already
out on the street.
Case in point... The
two motherfuckers
making it they business
to fuck you up.
If those fools get outta
pocket. I'm-a handle it.
But until then. that's still
just a straight up "if."
Hey. JJ's dead.
Wait a sec. What? One
of Karvel's boys.
Got lit up this morning.
both him and his girl.
Shit could've gone down
any number of ways.
It's true.
I ain't gonna fret till
I know the whole story.
Hey. man. Bump all that.
Let's talk about what's
really got you trippin'.
You cats mind?
(The Final Solution's
Brotherman playing)
I break up anything important?
We just bullshitting. Mm-hmm.
You know. them cats been at your
heels since you could walk.
I remember that one time.
you wasn't but 4...
What you want. Pop? Me?
You the one showed up
down at the clink.
♪ Brotherman
Must've been lookin'
for somethin'.
♪ Brotherman
♪♪
(sniffs)
How'd you find me?
Went down by the overpass.
- Your boy Curtis pointed me.
- Ah. good man. Curtis.
Yeah. that's stretchin' it.
Took me for 20 bucks
before tellin' me a thing.
Ah. well. I'll get you
back for that. but. uh...
Now bail's a different story.
Forgot about it. man.
In fact. forget I came
down there at all.
Well. I'm here now. Might as
well get your money's worth.
Noticed you had a few choice
words with Jerome earlier.
Wanna start with that?
Or with whoever did
that shit to your face.
Happened on a job. Ah.
Uh. which one?
Stocking the shelves
for the Koreans
or slingin' for your uncle?
♪♪
Now I-I-I didn't
come here to judge.
I'm just sayin'... Shut...
shut the fuck up. man.
Huh?
I don't need to hear any of it.
Shut the fuck up? Yeah.
shut the fuck up.
I don't need to
hear you're sorry.
I don't need to hear any
of that shit. Sorry?
What the fuck I got
to be sorry about?
That's all I've ever done.
All I've ever wanted to
do was be my own man.
And I couldn't be ashamed
of that if I wanted to.
I've got news for you. What
you are ain't a fucking man.
Okay. and you would know.
That it?
Shit.
You ain't got a fucking clue.
'Cause if you did. then why'd
you come looking for me?
♪♪
(fireworks exploding
and whistling)
Oh. shit! (dogs barking)
Damn!
(fireworks popping
and whistling)
(breathing slowly)
(bird squawking)
She wanted me to
give this to you.
Presumably. she meant while you
were alive. I guess. but...
I don't know. I don't know.
I don't...
know...
if it make any difference.
I don't think...
that actually seeing your kid...
would make it hurt less.
(ragged breathes)
Well...
I never thought that
would be how it ends.
Hey. Al...
Oh. my God.
Are you okay?
Hey. Can you hear me?
ALEJANDRO: Jesus.
We are farmers first.
Grow the product.
bring it across the
border. distribute.
Do everything possible
to avoid conflict.
RAMIRO: Including only working
with people that we trust.
And we've had some
issues with that lately.
Pedro mentioned this to you?
Sí. señor.
You have any thoughts on that?
No. señor.
We might need some new
people moving forward.
Assuming my son hasn't
misjudged you...
(speaks Spanish)
I mean. besides money.
You want power. just
like everyone else.
You work with us long
enough. you might get some.
You cross us. we crush you.
Then get the fuck out.
(footsteps depart)
(door opens. closes)
(inhales deeply. exhales slowly)
(gulping) (water sloshing)
(exhales sharply)
Think it'll hold?
It'll be fine for take off.
We'll see what happens
when we try to land.
(exhales)
(gasps. sniffs)
TEDDY: I'm never coming
back to this fucking place.
Never should've landed
here to begin with.
Let's get the fuck outta here.
(speaks Spanish)
(exhales. sniffs)
♪ Hey!
(Robert Moore's Everything's
Gonna Be Alright playing)
(indistinct conversations)
Hey. I got some M80s that
I'm-a fire off. too.
but Cissy say ain't no
fireworks for me right now.
(siren whoops)
(car doors open)
(police radio chatter)
Who owns the house?
It's my motherfucking house.
CISSY: All right.
Problem. officers?
Been reports of gunshots
being fired of a roof.
It's just fireworks.
We do it every year.
And the open containers?
The weed?
That all part of the
yearly ritual as well?
(laughs) Hey. yo. you real? You for real?
Look... Jerome.
It's Independence Day.
You check your attitude.
It's Independence Day. though.
You need to check these nuts!
Franklin. Ah. ah! Ah. ah. ah!
We're not doing this. Not today.
All right?
Let me go. Uh. sir?
FRANKLIN: Hold this for me.
CISSY: I'm not moving
till we have a civil
goddamn conversation.
Come on now.
Wanna have a drink. Hey. wait!
What the fuck you... (grunts)
JEROME: Come on. man! FRANKLIN: Get off!
Get off of me!
(shouting continues)
JEROME: Get off him. man!
(gun cocks) I will shoot!
Back off!
(Louie shouting indistinctly)
MAN: He can't fucking breathe!
JEROME: Hey. you...
You let him go!
(ragged breath)
- He's got a gun!
- Let him go!
- Hey. yo. let go. man!
(siren wailing)
(tires screech) MAN: Hold up!
Hold up!
ANDRE: Come on. bro. We got this.
We got this.
(Louie shouts indistinctly)
ANDRE: What are you doing. man?
What the hell are y'all doing?
Put that thing away! (coughing)
Get in the car. Fuck
you. pigs. man!
(Franklin gasping)
Fuck you. pig!
(radio static) Franklin.
Breathe. Franklin.
Hey. boy. get away
from my nephew. boy.
Stop!
Stop! Knock his ass out. boy.
(gasps)
Franklin. breathe.
Melody.
(Franklin wheezing)
I got you. (continues wheezing)
Just breathe. Franklin.
It's okay.
I got you.
♪♪
(indistinct conversations)
WOMAN: ♪ Bionic lover
♪ Bionic lover
(raspy voice) Yeah.
The ice makes it better.
You sound awful.
It sounds worse than it feels.
For real? Fuck. naw.
It hurts like hell.
(laughs. wheezing)
He say anything before leaving?
Mnh-mnh.
You all right?
I'm straight.
For real.
♪ Ooh. ooh
I should've told you. Hmm.
And I'm gonna make
back that $200.
(fireworks exploding
and whistling)
None of that matters now.
I just wanna sit here...
(fireworks whistling)
and enjoy this minute.
♪♪
(cheering)
(Explosions and
whistling continue)
♪♪
Yeah. I know.
Your uncle and your cousin...
(speaks Spanish)
The only one who's
not is tu papá.
(cheering. fireworks pop)
I like him.
Check out the balls on your boy.
going after the big
fish like that. huh?
(scoffs) In his dreams.
(chuckles)
It's not like her to
cavort with the help.
Maybe he's packing
something special.
Nah. he's a fucking ape.
(laughs)
He's an ape that has
her pretty little ear.
Think I can trust him?
Yeah. (Sniffs)
Yeah. you can trust him.
(sniffs) The way we
trusted Enrique.
Look what happened there.
You never have to worry
about me like that.
You do know that. right?
There's nothing I wouldn't do for you.
(Sniffles)
That I love you.
You've clearly had too much to drink.
Too much.
(sniffles)
(explosions continue)
♪♪
(indistinct conversations)
(speaks Spanish) ...who can
help us just on the product.
You're not gonna like them.
I wanna be full partner
with you and Pedro.
(laughs) Now you sound crazy.
No. I don't.
I already killed
two people. Lucia.
I followed you. and
I didn't have to.
How long you'll last with Pedro
and your sorority sisters.
Pedro's not gonna like it.
Pedro's not gonna like it?
No.
Okay.
If this works.
you'll get your fair share.
♪♪
(engine roaring)
(filtered voice) She asked
me to give this to you.
Okay. last time. I swear. Um...
you sure we're good down there?
(filtered voice)
I've been thinking.
If we're backed by the CIA.
what does it matter if
we're good down there?
That's... a good point.
Yeah.
(wind howling)
(Funkadelic's Can You
Get to That playing)
(indistinct conversations)
(snoring)
LEON: Hey. come on. homie. What
you grabbing on my shirt for?
KEVIN: Hey. you got this.
Hey. Hey.
(Leon speaks indistinctly)
- Get down! (Laughs)
- (Kevin laughs)
- Oh. shit.
- Ah! Oh. man.
Hey. you know it's a good party
when the fucking
roof catch fire.
(laughing) It's
high as hell. man.
Oh. man.
(liquor splashes)
Hey. why you pouring
out good liquor. man?
Whatcha doin'? Hey. that's
for the dead homies.
Oh. (liquor splashes)
And what's that for? All
the ladies that ain't had
the pleasure of my
company. nigga.
Nigga. you gonna need
a bigger bottle.
Be real. (Laughs)
Hey. Kev. That ain't funny.
What's up?
(chuckles)
Tomorrow morning.
think I can borrow your
auntie car for a few hours?
♪♪
Probably. Why?
So we don't have to
take a bus to Avi's.
♪♪
(laughing) Hey. man!
Hey. I love you. man!
(laughter) I love you. man!
Oh. my bad. Hey. my bad.
Hey. hey.
♪ Signed "insufficient funds"
♪ Can you get
♪ I want to know
♪ I wanna know if you
can get to that ♪
♪ Can you get
♪ Can you get to that
♪ I wanna know if you
can get to that ♪
♪ Can you get
♪ I want to know
♪ I wanna know if you
can get to that ♪
♪ Can you get to that
♪ Can you get
♪ I wanna know if you
can get to that ♪
♪ Can you get
♪ I wanna know if you
can get to that ♪
♪ When you base your
life on credit ♪
♪ And your lovin'
days are done ♪
♪ Checks you signed with
a-love and kisses ♪
♪ Later come back signed
"insufficient funds" ♪
♪ Yeah. get to that
♪ Can you get
♪ I want to know
♪♪
Captions by VITA...